Sculpture Lantern Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Sculpture Lantern Slide Collection
1900-1960
VRC 2100
Yale University Arts Library
38.6
116 boxes
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of sculpture.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white glass lantern slides of sculpture.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by nationality individual artist name. Sub-divided primarily by location of the work. Some sections are preceded by an Anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Sculpture; Photographs; Reproductions
- Pre-Historic Paleolithic Europe (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
    - Paleolithic (Box 1)
      - Mobile Art (Box 1)
        - Human Figures (Box 1)
      - Venus of Willendorf (Box 1)
        - Weapons & Tools (Box 1)
      - Site and Monuments (Box 1)
    - Cities (Box 1)
      - Altamira, Spain (Box 1)
      - Font DeGaume (Box 1)
      - Lascaux, France (Box 1)
        - Axial Gallery (Box 1)
        - Nave (Box 1)
        - Rotunda (Box 1)
        - Pit or Shaft (Box 1)
      - Laussel, France (Box 2)
        - "Venus" of Laussel (Box 2)
      - Montespan, France (Box 2)
      - Niaux, France (Box 2)
      - Pech-Merle, France (Box 2)
      - Teyjat, France (Box 2)
- Prehistoric Neolithic (Box 2)
  - General (Box 2)
    - Mobile Art (Box 2)
    - Sites & Monuments (by Area) (Box 2)
  - Africa (Box 2)
  - South Africa (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
    - Drakensberg (Box 2)
  - Tassili (Box 2)
  - Europe (Box 2)
    - Various (Box 2)
    - Britain (Box 2–3)
      - Avebury (Box 3)
      - Stonehenge (Box 3)
      - Woodhenge (Box 3)
    - France (Box 3)
      - Carnac (Box 3)
      - Lochmariaquer (Box 3)
    - Malta (Box 3)
    - Sardinia (Box 3)
    - Scandinavia (Box 3)
    - Sicily (Box 3–4)
    - Spain (Box 4)
  - Near East (Box 4)
    - Hacilar (Box 4)
  - General Techniques (Box 4)
- Egypt (Box 4)
  - General (Box 4)
  - Pre-Dynastic (Box 4)
  - Early Dynastic I-III (Box 4)
  - Old Kingdom IV-VI (Box 4)
    - Figures (Box 4)
      - Various (Box 4)
      - Ranofer (Box 4)
      - Khufu (Box 4)
      - Mycerinus & His wife (Box 4)
      - Pepi I & His Son (Box 4)
      - Seated Krafe with Falcon (Box 4)
      - Rahotep & Nofret (Box 4)
      - Seated Scribe (Box 5)
      - Seneb & Family (Box 5)
      - Shelkh (Box 5)
      - Kafre (Box 5)
    - Heads (Box 5)
    - Reliefs (Box 5)
      - Various (Box 5)
      - Mycerinus & Hathor & Goddness (Box 5)
      - Tomb of Ptahotep (Box 5)
      - Tomb of Ti (Box 5)
    - 1st Intermediate Period 7th – 10th century, 2258-2052 B.C. (Box 5)
    - Middle Kingdom 11th - 12th century, 2134-1786 B.C. (Box 5)
      - Animals (Box 5)
      - Figures (Box 5)
      - Heads (Box 6)
      - Relief (Box 6)
    - 2nd Intermediate Period 13th –17th century, 1786-1750 B.C. (Box 6)
    - Empire or New Kingdom (Box 6)
      - Tomb of Tutankhamen (Box 6)
        - Various (Box 6)
        - Animals (Box 6)
        - Female Figures (Box 6–7)
        - Male Figures (Box 7)
          - Various (Box 7)
          - Amarna Period (Box 7)
          - Amenhotep (Box 7)
          - Colossi of Memnon (Box 7)
        - Groups (Box 7)
        - Heads (Box 7)
          - Various (Box 7)
          - Amarna Period Heads (Box 7–8)
        - Reliefs (Box 8)
          - Various (Box 8)
          - Amarna Period Reliefs (Box 8)
      - Abydos (Box 8–9)
      - Der-El-Bahri (Box 9)
      - Karnak (Box 9)
        - Various (Box 9)
        - Temple of Amon (Box 9)
      - Luxor (Box 9)
      - Medinet Abu (Box 9)
        - Various (Box 9)
        - Sphinxes (Box 9)
- Late Period (Box 9)
  - Various (Box 9)
  - Dynasty 21st –25th, 1085-663 B.C. (Box 9)
  - Saite Period (Box 9)
  - Ptolemaic Period (Box 9)
  - Greco-Roman Period, 30th B.C.-395 A.D. (Box 9–10)
- Near East (Box 10)
  - Anatolia (Box 10)
    - Hittite (Box 10)
  - Mesopotamia (Box 10)
    - Sumerian (Box 10)
      - Gudea (Box 10)
      - Warka Head (Box 10)
      - Ur-Ningursu (Box 10)
      - Stele of Naram-Sin (Box 10)
    - Babylonian (Box 10–11)
    - Assyrian (Box 11)
      - Animals (Box 11)
      - Figures (Box 11)
      - Relief (Box 11)
        - Various (Box 11)
        - Khorsabad, Palace of Aragon (Box 11)
        - Nimrud, Palace of Assurnasipal (Box 11)
        - Nineveh, Palace of Ashurbanipal (Box 11)
          - Various (Box 11)
          - Lion Hunt (Box 11)
            - Various (Box 11)
            - Wounded Lions (Box 11)
            - Small Lion Hunt (Box 11)
        - Nineveh, Palace of Senacherib (Box 11)
  - Ancient Persia (Box 11–12)
  - Syria (Box 12)
  - Phoenicia (Box 12)
- Early Medieval (Box 12)
- Round (Box 12)
  - Various (Box 12)
  - 3rd century (Box 12)
  - 4th century (Box 12)
    - Various (Box 12)
    - Figures (Box 12)
      - Various (Box 12)
      - Julian the Apostate (Box 12)
      - Seated Christ (Box 12)
      - Emperor Valentinian (bronze) (Box 12)
      - Valentinianus (Box 12)
    - Heads (Box 12)
      - Various (Box 12)
      - Colossal Head of Constantius (bronze) (Box 12)
  - 5th century (Box 12)
- Relief (Box 12)
  - Various (Box 12)
  - S. Maria Panachrantos (Box 13)
  - 4th century (Box 13)
    - Obelisk of Theodosius (Box 13)
  - 5th century (Box 13)
    - Various (Box 13)
    - S. Sabine, Rome (Box 13)
  - 6th century (Box 13)
  - 7th century (Box 13)
  - 8th century (Box 13)
  - 10th century (Box 13)
  - 11th century (Box 13)
  - 12th century (Box 13)
  - 13th century (Box 13)
- Sarcophagi (Box 13)
  - Various (Box 13)
  - Arles Sarcophagi (Box 13)
  - Paris Sarcophagi (Box 13)
  - 3rd century (Box 13)
    - Various (Box 13)
    - Ravenna (Box 13)
    - Rome Sarcophagi (Box 13)
      - Various (Box 13)
      - S. Maria Antigua (Box 14)
      - Johan Sarcophagi (Box 14)
      - Hertofile Sarcophagi (Box 14)
  - 4th century (Box 14)
    - Ales (Box 14)
    - Milan (Box 14)
    - Rome (Box 14)
      - Various (Box 14)
      - Lazarus & Peter (Box 14)
      - Lateran 174 Columnar Front (Box 14)
      - Sarcophagus of Good Shepherd & Vintage Scene (Box 14)
      - Sarcophagus of Junius Bassus (Box 15)
      - Sarcophagus of Constantia (Box 15)
      - Sarcophagus of S. Helena (Box 15)
      - Trinity Sarcophagus (Box 15)
      - Two Brothers Sarcophagus (Box 15)
    - Syracuse (Box 15)
  - 5th century (Box 15)
  - 6th century (Box 15)
  - 7th century (Box 15)
  - 8th century (Box 15)
- Anglo-Saxon (Box 15)
- Celtic (Box 16)
- Scandinavian (Box 16)
- Merovingian (Box 16)
  - 5th century (Box 16)
  - 6th century (Box 16)
  - 7th century (Box 16)
- Carolingian (Box 16)
  - Various (Box 16)
  - Reliefs (Box 16)
  - Sarcophagi (Box 16)
- Pre-Romanesque (Box 16–17)
  - Dura-Europos (Box 17)
  - Gallo-Roman (Box 17)
  - Coptic (Box 17)
- Austria (Box 17)
  - Grupello, Gabriel (Box 17)
  - Luchsperger, Lorenz (Box 17)
  - Wotruba, Fritz, 1907- (Box 17)
- Belgium (Box 17)
  - Various Artists (Box 17)
  - Meunier, Constantine Emile, 1831-1905 (Box 18)
- Britain (Box 18)
  - Various Artists (Box 18)
  - 11th Century (Box 18)
  - Gothic (Box 18)
    General
    Xx Tomb for Henry VII see also Sculpture Italy, Pietro, Torrigiano
  - Renaissance (Box 18)
  - 19th Century (Box 18)
  - 20th Century (Box 18)
    - Ady, Thomas (Box 18)
    - Agar, Eileen, 1904- (Box 18)
    - Armitage, Kenneth, 1916- (Box 18)
    - Bacon, Henry (Box 18)
    - Bacon, John, 1740-1799 (Box 18)
    - Banks, Thomas, 1735-1805 (Box 18)
    - Bedford, Richard, 1883-1967 (Box 18)
    - Butler, Reginald, 1913- (Box 18)
    - Caro, Anthony, 1924- (Box 18)
    - Chadwick, Lynn, 1914- (Box 19)
    - Crake (Box 19)
    - Dobson, Frank, 1886-1963 (Box 19)
    - Drury, Alfred (Box 19)
    - Epstein, Jacob, 1880-1959 (Box 19)
    - Flaxman, John, 1755-1826 (Box 19)
    - Ford, Onslow, 1852-1901 (Box 19)
    - Frampton, Sir George (Box 19)
    - Gibson, Grinling (Box 19)
      Xx for woodcarving & Architecture Renaissance Britain, see Ornament
    - Gibson, John, 1790-1866 (Box 19)
    - Gilbert, Alfred, 1854-1934 (Box 19)
    - Gill, Eric, 1882-1940 (Box 19–20)
    - Hart, Barry (Box 20)
    - Hepworth, Barbara, 1903-1975 (Box 20)
    - Holding, Eileen (Box 20)
    - Jagger, Charles Sargent, 1885-1934 (Box 20)
    - Kent, William (Box 20)
    - Lynn-Jenkis, Krank, 1870-1927 (Box 20)
    - Marchand, David, 1674-1726 (Box 20)
    - Marshall, Edward, 1598-1674 (Box 20)
    - McMillan, William (Box 20)
    - McWilliam, F.E., 1909- (Box 20)
    - Moore, Henry, 1898-1986 (Box 20)
      X Moore, Henry Spencer
      - Before 192 (Box 20)
      - -1930 (Box 20)
      - 1931-1939 (Box 20)
      - 1940-1949 (Box 20)
      - 1950-1954 (Box 20–21)
      - 1955- (Box 21)
    - Nash, David, 1945- (Box 21)
    - Nicholson, Ben, 1894- (Box 21)
    - Paolozzi, Eduardo Luigi, 1924- (Box 21)
    - Parr, Harry (Box 21)
    - Pearson, Lionel (Box 21)
    - Sagar, John (Box 21)
    - Skeaping, John (Box 21)
    - Smith, Percy J. (Box 21)
    - Stevens, Alfred (Box 21)
    - Stone, Nicholas, 1586-1647 (Box 21)
    - Underwood, Leon, 1890-1975 (Box 21)
    - Westmacott, Sir Richard (Box 21)
    - Wilton, Joseph, 1722-1803 (Box 21)
    - Woolner, Thomas, 1825-1892 (Box 21)
- Czechoslovakia (Box 21)
  - Various Artists (Box 21)
- Denmark (Box 21)
  - Various Artists (Box 21)
  - Cibber, Cajus Gabriel, 1630-1700 (Box 21)
  - Thorwaldsen, Bartel, 1770-1844 (Box 21)
    - Copenhagen (Box 21)
    - Lucerne (Box 21)
    - Rome (Box 21)
- Flanders (Box 22)
  - Various (Box 22)
  - 16th century (Box 22)
  - Baerze, Jacques de (Box 22)
  - Borreman, Jan (Box 22)
  - Duquesnoy, Francois, 1594-1643 (Box 22)
  - Jean de la Mer (Box 22)
  - Jongling (Box 22)
  - Massys, Jan (Box 22)
  - Renier de Huy (Box 22)
  - Scheemaeckers, Peter II, 1691-1781 (Box 22)
  - Tassaert, Jean-Pierre, 1727-1788 (Box 22)
- France (Box 22)
  - Romanesque (Box 22)
    - General (Box 22)
    - Toulouse (Box 22)
      - Various (Box 22)
      - S. Sernin (Box 22–23)
    - Diagrams (Box 23)
    - Capitals (Box 23)
    - Crucifixes (Box 23)
    - Tombs (Box 23)
    - Tympani (Box 23)
    - 11th Century (Box 23)
    - 12th Century (Box 23)
      - Baptismal Fonts (Box 23)
        Xx for baptismal font from Liege, see under Sculpture Flanders, Ranier de Huy
      - Capitals (Box 23)
      - Crucifixions (Box 23)
      - Figures (Box 23)
        - Various (Box 23)
        - Angers figures (Yale Gallery) (Box 23–24)
        - Virgin & Child (Box 24)
      - Heads (Box 24)
      - Reliefs (Box 24)
        - Various Titles (Box 24)
        - Saint Denis (Box 24)
  - Gothic (Box 24)
    - General (Box 24)
    - 13th Century (Box 24)
      - Figures (Box 24)
        - Various (Box 24)
        - Angels (Box 24)
        - Virgin & Child (Box 24)
      - Heads (Box 24)
      - Misericords & Stalls (Box 24)
      - Reliefs (Box 24)
      - Tombs (Box 24–25)
    - 14th Century (Box 25)
      - General (Box 25)
      - Figures (Box 25)
        - Various (Box 25)
        - Virgin & Child (Box 25)
      - Forgery (Box 25)
      - Heads (Box 25)
      - Misericords & Stalls (Box 25)
      - Retables (Box 25)
      - Tombs (Box 25–26)
    - 15th Century (Box 26)
      - General (Box 26)
      - Entombments (Box 26)
      - Figures (Box 26)
        - Various (Box 26)
        - Virgin & Child (Box 26)
      - Heads (Box 26)
      - Misericords & Stalls (Box 26)
      - Pieta (Box 26)
      - Reliefs (Box 26)
        - Various (Box 26)
        - Angels (Box 26–27)
      - Retables (Box 27)
      - Tombs (Box 27)
        - Tomb of Jeans Sans Peur (Box 27)
        - Tomb of Philippe Pot (Box 27)
        - Tomb of Philippe Le Hardi (Box 27)
  - Renaissance (Box 27)
    - Various (Box 27)
    - 16th Century (Box 27)
      - Various (Box 27)
      - Figures (Box 27)
        - Various (Box 27)
        - Virgin & Child (Box 27)
      - Heads (Box 27)
      - Misericords & Stalls (Box 27)
      - Retables (Box 27)
      - School of Troyes (Box 27)
      - Tombs (Box 27)
    - 17th Century (Box 28)
    - 18th Century (Box 28)
    - 19th - 20th Century (Box 28)
      - Various Artists (Box 28)
      - Adam, Jacob-Sigisbert (Box 28)
      - Adam, Lambert Sigisbert, 1670-1747 (Box 28)
      - Allegrain, Christophe-G., 1710-1795 (Box 28)
      - Anguier, Francois (Box 28)
      - Anguir, Michel, 1612-1686 (Box 28)
      - Arcis, Marc, 1652-1739 (Box 28)
      - Arp, Jean Hans, 1887-1966 (Box 28)
      - Aube (Box 28)
      - Barrias (Box 28)
      - Bartholdi, Frederic A., 1834-1904 (Box 28)
      - Bartholome (Box 29)
      - Barye, Antoine (Box 29)
      - Beauneveu, Andre, 1360-1403 (Box 29)
      - Bernard, Joseph (Box 29)
      - Bigarelli, 1498-156 (Box 29)
      - Blassel, Nicolas, 1600-1659 (Box 29)
      - Botemps, Pierre (Box 29)
      - Bosio, Francois J., 1769-1845 (Box 29)
      - Bouchard, Henri (Box 29)
      - Bouchardon, Edme, 1698-1762 (Box 29)
      - Boucher, Alfred (Box 29)
      - Bourdelle, Emile Antoine, 1861-1929 (Box 29)
      - Bourdin, Michael (Box 29)
      - Braque, George, 1881-1963 (Box 30)
      - Caffieri, Jean Jacques., 1725-1792 (Box 30)
      - Carpeaux, Jean-Baptiste, 1827-1875 (Box 30)
      - Carpentas (Box 30)
      - Carrier-Belleuse, A.E., 1824-1887 (Box 30)
      - Cesar, Baldiccini1921- (Box 30)
      - Chapu, Henri (Box 30)
      - Charpentier (Box 30)
      - Chaudet, Antoine Denis, 1763-1810 (Box 30)
      - Clodion, Claude M., 1738-1814 (Box 30)
      - Collet, Anne Marie, 1748-1821 (Box 30)
      - Colombe, Michel, 1430-1512 (Box 30–31)
      - Cordier, Charles-Henri-Joseph, 1827-1903 (Box 31)
      - Cornu, Sebastien M., 1804-1871 (Box 31)
      - Corot, Jean Pierre, 1784-1842 (Box 31)
      - Coustou, Guillaume I, 1677-1746 (Box 31)
      - Coustou, Nicolas, 1658-1733 (Box 31)
      - Coysevox, Antoine, 1640-1720 (Box 31)
      - Dalou, Aime-Jules, 1838-1900 (Box 31)
      - Daumier, Honore, 1808-1879 (Box 31)
      - David D'Angers, P.J., 1788-1856 (Box 31)
      - Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917 (Box 31–32)
      - Delaplanche (Box 32)
      - Delaunay, Robert, 1885-1941 (Box 32)
      - Derbais (Box 32)
      - Desjardins, Martin, 1636-1694 (Box 32)
      - Despiau, Charles (Box 32)
      - Devilliers, R. (Box 32)
      - Doublemard (Box 32)
      - Dubois, Paul, 1829-1905 (Box 32)
      - Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968 (Box 32)
      - Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, 1876-1918 (Box 32)
      - Etex, Antoine, 1808-1888 (Box 33)
      - Falconet, Etienne Maurice, 1716-1791 (Box 33)
      - Falguiere, Alexandre, 1831-1900 (Box 33)
      - Francavilla, Pietro (Box 33)
      - Francin, Guillaume, 1741-1830 (Box 33)
      - Fremiet, Emmanuel, 1824-1911 (Box 33)
      - Gaudier-Brzeska, Henri, 1891-1915 (Box 33)
      - Gauguin, Paul, 1848-1903 (Box 33)
      - Gericault, Theodore, 1791-1824 (Box 33)
      - Gerome, Jean Leon (Box 33)
      - Girardon, Francois, 1628-1715 (Box 33–34)
      - Guillaume, J.B.C. (Box 34)
      - Goujon, Jean, 1510-1568 (Box 34)
      - Guerin, Guilles (Box 34)
      - Guillain, Simen (Box 34)
      - Guiramand, Jean de Toulon (Box 34)
      - Houdon, Jean Antoine, 1741-1828 (Box 34–35)
        - Various (Box 35)
        - Aix (Box 35)
        - Angers (Box 35)
        - Baltimore (Box 35)
        - Boston (Box 35)
        - Montpelier (Box 35)
        - Mt. Vernon (Box 35)
        - Nevers (Box 35)
        - New Haven (Box 35)
        - New York (Box 36)
          - Various (Box 36)
          - Metropolitan Museum (Box 36)
        - Paris (Box 36)
          - Comedie Francois (Box 36)
          - Louvre (Box 36)
        - Richmond (Box 36)
        - Washington (Box 36)
      - Jacquet, Mathieu, b. 1550 (Box 37)
        Xx for entire picture of Belle Cheminee, see Arc. Ren. France, Fontainebleau Chateau
      - Jean De Cambrai, d. 1438 (Box 37)
      - Juste Family Jean & Antoine (Box 37)
      - Kaeppelin, Philippe (Box 37)
      - Keller (Box 37)
      - Lamour, Jean B. (Box 37)
      - Landowski, Paul Maximilian (Box 37)
      - Laurens, Henri, 1885-1954 (Box 37)
      - Le Clerc & S. Priest, J. (Box 37)
      - Le Corbusier (Box 37)
      - Legros, Pierre, 1629-1714 (Box 37)
      - Le Lorrain, Robert, 1666-1743 (Box 37)
      - Lemoyne, Jean-Baptiste, 1704-1778 (Box 37)
      - Leygue, Louis, 1905- (Box 37)
      - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973 (Box 37)
        - Various (Box 37–38)
        - Collection of the artists (Box 38)
        - New Haven (Box 38)
        - New York (Box 38)
        - Paris (Box 38)
        - Philadelphia (Box 38)
      - Maillol, Aristide, 1861-1944 (Box 38)
        - Various (Box 38–39)
        - New Haven (Box 39)
        - New York (Box 39)
        - Washington (Box 39)
      - Marsy, Balthazar & Gaspard (Box 39)
      - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954 (Box 39)
        - Baltimore (Box 39)
        - New Haven (Box 39)
        - New York (Box 39)
      - Michel, Jean & Sonnette, G. de la (Box 39)
      - Moitte, Jean-Guillaume, 1746-1810 (Box 39)
      - Morel, Jacques (Box 39)
      - Orloff, Chana (Box 39)
      - Pajou, Augustin, 1730-1809 (Box 39)
        - Various (Box 39)
        - Paris (Box 39–40)
      - Pelle, Honore (Box 40)
      - Petitot, Pierre, 1760-1840 (Box 40)
      - Philibert De L'Orme (Box 40)
      - Pigalle, Jean-Baptiste, 1714-1785 (Box 40)
      - Pilon, Germain, 1535-1590 (Box 40)
      - Prieur, Barthelemy, ca.1611- (Box 40)
      - Prou, Jacques, 1655-1706 (Box 40)
      - Puech, Denys (Box 40)
      - Puget, Pierre, 1620-1694 (Box 40)
      - Regnault & Chaleveau (Box 41)
      - Renoir, Pierre-Auguste, 1841-1919 (Box 41)
      - Richier, Germaine, 1904-1959 (Box 41)
      - Richier, Ligier, ca.1500-1567 (Box 41)
      - Rochet, Louis, 1813-1880 (Box 41)
      - Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917 (Box 41)
        - General (Box 41)
        - Figures (Box 41)
          - Various (Box 41)
          - Adam (Box 41)
          - Age of Bronze (Box 41)
          - Balzac (full length) (Box 41–42)
          - Caryatid (Box 42)
          - Crouching woman (Box 42)
          - Danaide (Box 42)
          - Dance Movement (Box 42)
          - Eve (Box 42)
          - Old Courtesan (Box 42)
          - Prodigal Son (Box 42)
          - S. John the Baptiste (Box 42)
          - The Thinker (Box 42)
          - Torsos (Box 42)
          - The Walking man (Box 42)
        - Gates of Hell (Box 42)
        - Groups (Box 42)
          - Burghers of Calais (Box 42)
          - Call to Arms (Box 42–43)
        - Hands (Box 43)
        - Heads (Box 43)
          - Various (Box 43)
          - Balzac (Box 43)
          - Bellona (Box 43)
          - Clemenceau (Box 43)
          - Dalou (Box 43)
      - Roland, Philippe-L., 1746-1816 (Box 43)
      - Roubiliac, Louis Francois, 1695-1762 (Box 43)
      - Rude, Francois, 1784-1855 (Box 43–44)
      - Saint-Marceaux, Rene de (Box 44)
      - Saly, Jacques, 1717-1776 (Box 44)
      - Sarebezolle (Box 44)
      - Sluter, Claus, ca.1375-1405 (Box 44)
        - Dijon (Chartreusse de Champol) (Box 44)
          - Portal Group (Box 44)
          - Tomb of Jean Sans Peur (Box 44)
          - Tomb of Philippe le Hardi (Box 44)
          - Well of Moses (Box 44)
        - New York (Box 44)
      - Spoerri, Daniel, 1930- (Box 44)
      - Varin, Jean (Box 44)
      - Vasselot, Marquet de (Box 44)
      - Veyrier, Christopher (Box 44)
      - Werve, Clause de (Box 44)
- Germany (Box 44)
  - Romanesque (Box 44)
    - Various Titles (Box 44–45)
    - Halberstadt (Box 45)
    - Hildesheim (Box 45)
      - Baptistmal Font (Box 45)
      - Bronze Column (Box 45)
      - Bronze Door (Box 45)
    - Werden (Box 45)
  - Gothic (Box 45)
    - Various Titles (Box 45)
    - Emund (Box 45)
    - 13th Century (Box 45)
      - Various Titles (Box 45)
    - 14th century (Box 45)
      - Various Titles (Box 45–46)
      - Perpignan Crucifixion (Box 46)
      - Thorn Madonna (Box 46)
      - Master of Wolfskehl (Box 46)
      - Cologne Master (Box 46)
    - 15th Century (Box 46)
      - Various Titles (Box 46)
      - Dangolsheim Madonna Master (Box 46)
      - Master of Kefermarkt (Box 46)
      - Middle Rhine (Box 46)
      - Master of Northern Germany (Box 46)
      - Nurnberg Master (Box 46)
      - Swabian Master (Box 47)
      - Upper Rhine (Box 47)
  - Reinassance (Box 47)
    - 16th & 17th Century (Box 47)
      - Various Titkes (Box 47)
      - Deathmask of Frederick the Great (Box 47)
      - Master of Mauer (Box 47)
      - Master of Zwettl, Altar, 1519 (Box 47)
      - Master H.L., ac. 1511-1526 (Box 47)
      - Tomb of Maximilian (Box 47)
    - 18th – 20th Centuries (Box 47)
      - Various Titles (Box 47)
      - Known Artists (Box 47)
      - Arp, Hans, 1887-1966 (Box 47)
        Xx Sculpture France
      - Asam, Egid Quirin, 1692-1750 (Box 47)
      - Backhoffen, Hans (Box 47)
      - Barlach, Ernst, 1870-1938 (Box 47)
        - Various (Box 47–48)
        - Gustrow Catle (Box 48)
      - Bauer, Johann L. (Box 48)
      - Belling, Rudolf, 1886- (Box 48)
      - Braun, Matthias, 1684-1738 (Box 48)
      - Breker, Arno, 1900- (Box 48)
      - Christian, Johann J., 1706-1777 (Box 48)
      - Dannecker, Johann, 1758-1841 (Box 48)
      - Dannecker, Johan Heinrich von, 1758-1841 (Box 48)
      - Dell, Peter (the elder), b.1501 (Box 48)
      - Dowfermann, Heinrich, ac.1510-1544 (Box 48)
      - Durer, Albrecht, 1471-1528 (Box 48)
      - Eimbeck, Conrad von (Box 48)
      - Ernst, Max, 1891-1976 (Box 48)
      - Feichtmeyer, Joseph A., 1696-1770 (Box 48)
      - De Fiore, Ernesto (Box 48)
      - Flotnner, Peter, 1485-1546 (Box 48)
      - Gerhaert, Nicholas, 1462-1473 (Box 48)
      - Goeritz, Mattias (Box 48)
      - Gotz, Joseph Matthias, 1696-1760 (Box 48)
      - Grasser, Erasmus, 1450-1526 (Box 48)
        - Various (Box 48)
        - Munich (Box 48)
      - Heckel, Erich, 1883-1970 (Box 48)
      - Heimann, E. (Box 48)
      - Hencke, Peter (Box 48)
      - Hildebrand, Adolf (Box 48)
      - Itten, Johannes, 1888- (Box 49)
      - Kaschauer, Jakob (Box 49)
      - Kirchner, Ernst, 1880-1938 (Box 49)
      - Klinger, Max, 1857-1920 (Box 49)
      - Koenig, Fritz, 1924- (Box 49)
      - Kolbe, George, 1877- (Box 49)
      - Kraft, Adam, 1450-1509 (Box 49)
      - Lackner, Andreas (Box 49)
      - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm von, 1881-1919 (Box 49)
        - Various Titles (Box 49)
        - Female Torso (Box 49)
        - Kneeling Woman (Box 49)
        - Meditation (Box 49–50)
        - Relief (Box 50)
        - Rising Youth (Box 50)
      - Leinsberger, Hans, ac.1513-1530 (Box 50)
      - Meit, Conrad, ac.1500-1544 (Box 50)
      - Merz, Gerhard, 1947- (Box 50)
      - Morgenster, Andreas (Box 50)
        Xx Sculpture Germany 15th c., Master the Zwettl Altar)
      - Multscher, Hans, 1400-1467 (Box 50)
      - Notke, Bernt, 1440-1509 (Box 50)
      - Obrist, Hermann, 1863-1927 (Box 50)
      - Pacher, Michael, 1435-1498 (Box 50)
      - Parler, Peter (Box 50)
      - Palermo, Blinky (Peter), 1943-1977 (Box 50)
      - Permoser, Balthasar, 1651-1732 (Box 50)
      - Pilgram, Franz A., 1460-1515 (Box 50)
      - Riemenschneider, Tilman, 1460-1531 (Box 50)
        - Various Titles (Box 50)
        - Altar of the Holy Blood (Box 50)
        - Wuzburg (Box 50)
        - Various Titles (Box 50)
          - Adam & Eve Figures (Box 50)
      - Schadow, J.Gottfried, 1764-1850 (Box 50)
      - Schardd, Edwin (Box 50)
      - Schluter, Andreas (Box 50)
      - Seyfer, Han von Hellbronn (Box 50)
      - Sporrer, Fidelis, 1733-1811 (Box 50)
      - Stoss, Veit, 1447-1542 (Box 50)
        - Various (Box 50)
        - Bamberg (Box 50–51)
        - Krakow (Box 51)
        - Nurnberg (Box 51)
          - Various (Box 51)
          - S. Lorenz (Box 51)
            - Annunciation (Salve Regina) (Box 51)
          - S. Sebald (Box 51)
            - Various (Box 51)
            - Crucifixion (Box 51)
            - S. Andrew (Box 51)
      - Straub, Johann B., 1704-1784 (Box 51)
      - Syrlin, Jorg (Box 51)
      - Tuaillon, Louis, 1862-1917 (Box 51)